gottman.com 2009-12-29

# The Gottman Institute - Contact Us- Privacy Policy

|  | 

## Gottman Institute Privacy Policy

The following provisions apply to information Gottman Institute learns about or obtains from You when You visit The Gottman Institute Web site (the “Site”). Your access or use of the Site constitutes Your legally binding acceptance of and agreement to this Privacy Policy. Definitions contained in the Site’s Terms shall apply to this Privacy Policy as well.

These provisions may be changed from time to time and without notice, at Gottman Institute’s sole discretion and as provided by applicable law. You should check this Privacy Policy frequently for any such changes, but in any case Your continued access or use of the Site shall constitute acceptance of any modifications of the Privacy Policy. Gottman Institute’s use of information gathered or obtained now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of such use.

### What We Collect

**You may see information collected about You via the Site, and delete or modify any personally identifiable information, such as Your name, e-mail address or home address or telephone number (“Personal Information”) by following ourCorrect/Update Procedure.**

**Information You Give Us:**   Gottman Institute receives and stores any information you enter on the Site (for example, when you register for one of our workshops, or purchase one of our products) or provide in any other manner, including via e-mail, including Personal Information. Of course, You can choose not to provide such information, but then You might not be able to register for a workshop or make a purchase on-line. Of course, you are always welcome to make such transactions by mail; The Gottman Institute, Inc., PO Box 15644, Seattle, WA 98115-0644 or telephone; (800) 523-6042 or (206) 523-9042. Gottman Institute uses the information that You provide for such purposes as facilitating Your purchase or workshop registration, responding to Your requests for information, improving the products and services we offer, and communicating with You.

Gottman Institute may, but is not obligated to, retain the content of any E-mails You send or information or data You provide by other means, including Your E-mail address and other personally identifiable information, so that Gottman Institute may respond to Your requests for information or questions, and comply with any legal requirements. Gottman Institute does not share our visitors Personal Information with any third parties, except as necessary for operation of the Site and provision of our products and services.

**Automated Information Collection:** Gottman Institute receives and stores certain types of information whenever You visit the Site. In addition to information You provide, we may collect the name of the domain and host from which You access the Internet; the IP address of the computer You are using; and the browser and operating system You are using; the date and time You access the Site; and the Internet address of the Web site from which You linked to the Site. [ADD ANY OTHER INFORMATION COLLECTED]  We use “cookies” to automatically gather some of this information. A cookie is a small text file that the Gottman Institute system sends to Your computer to collect information about Your activities on the Site. The cookie transmits this information back to the Site each time Your browser requests a page from the Site, and the information is stored to help facilitate Your use of the Site the next time You visit. If You do not want to receive cookies from the Site, You can set Your browser to not accept cookies.

### How We Use Information

We use the information You provide and we collect to:

  * Administer the Site and diagnose problems with our server;

  * Verify Your identity;

  * Provide You with information about the Site and Gottman Institute and our products and services; and in order to facilitate performance by Gottman Instiute or You under the Terms and any other agreement You may enter into with the Gottman Institute; and

  * Measure the number of visitors to the Site and how the Site is used, in order to make the Site as useful as possible to our visitors.

### Links

The Site may contain links to other sites. These links are for the convenience of visitors to the Site only, and Gottman Institute makes no representations whatsoever regarding such other sites. You should review the privacy policies of other sites carefully before providing any information to such sites. Gottman Institute is not responsible for the privacy policies or procedures or the content of any other site.

### Security

The Site has reasonable security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Gottman Institute’s control. [ADD INFORMATION ON THE TYPE OF SECURITY MEASURES USED BY GOTTMAN INSTITUTE]

### Compliance with COPPA

The Site is not directed at children under the age of 13. Gottman Institute complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and does not knowingly permit submission of Personal Information by anyone under 13 years of age.

### Subpoenas

Gottman Institute does not disclose the identities of visitors or users of the Site unless legally required to do so. We will respond to any subpoena received from a government agency (i.e., the Securities and Exchange Commission or law enforcement agencies) without prior notice to You. Unless prohibited by law or by a valid court order, we will notify You of any subpoena received from any other party (i.e., for civil litigation) which requires us to disclose Your identity, and will wait ten (10) days, or a lesser amount of time as required by the deadline in the subpoena, before providing the information requested by the subpoena.

### Correct/Update Procedure

If You want to delete or modify Your Personal Information or Automated Information from Gottman Institute’s records, You may do so by:

  * Sending an email to [gottman@gottman.com](mailto:gottman@gottman.com)

  * By mail to the following address: 

The Gottman Institute, Inc.  
P.O. Box 15644   
Seattle, WA 98115-0644 

  * By calling the following telephone number:  toll-free at (888) 523-9042 or (206) 523-9042 within Washington state. Fax number is (206) 729-0787.   

### Conditions of Use

Your access and use of the Site is subject to this Privacy Policy and [Web Site Terms](http://www.gottman.com/contact/legal/) including limitations on damages, and the applicability of the law of the State of Washington.

### Contacting the Site

If You have questions about this Privacy Policy, the Web Site Terms, or any other questions concerning the Site, please contact:

Webmaster

The Gottman Institute, Inc.  
P.O. Box 15644   
Seattle, WA 98115-0644 

|
